you are missing the most important thing
вы пропускаете мимо ушей самое главное
I am saying that in Russia they do not ban
что я говорю что в России не запрещают
any language and in Ukraine they ban it again and again not a
ни один язык а на Украине Запрещают ещё
single one we have bans No, come on
раз ещё раз ни одного у нас запрета Нет
and more no no no no Come on you
давай и больше нет нет нет нет Давай ты
now You are watching now yes yes and I
сейча Ты сейчас смотришь да да и я тебе
showed you that you do not have a single school yes
показал что у вас нету ни одной школы да
in national languages ​​What do you have
на национальных языках Что у вас
Banned they closed your Ukrainian
Запрещают у вас закрыли украинскую
library Yes the one you had they took and
библиотеку Да которая была у вас взяли и
this is what they are
это и
detaining people who go to the monument to
задерживают людей которые к памятнику
Lesya Ukrainka
Леси Украинки
Hello Good evening Where are you
Здравствуйте Добрый вечер вы
from Moscow Something is very bright for you for
откуда Из Москвы что-то вас сильно
Moscow well it's just that the light at home I
Москвы а ну это дома просто свет такой
understood and what do you talk about What do you talk about in
понял а чём общаетесь О чём общаетесь в
Moskvich Yes so far nothing just
Москвич Да пока ни о чём просто так
dropped in it's
заглянул
cool so far I haven't found any interesting
прикольно пока не находил интересных
interlocutors I found one girl
собеседников вот нашёл одну девушку
who said that she was from Belgorod
которая сказал что она из Белгорода вот
but she
но о на
lied And what are you talking about
врала А Вы о чём общаетесь
I'm from Belgorod I'm
я из Белгорода
also from Belgorod Well I'm definitely from
сам тоже из Белгорода Ну я точно из
Belgorod she I don't know where she
Белгорода она не знаю откуда
was from straight from the city of Belgorod I
была прямо из города Белгорода
live in
живу в
Kharkov Yes and how
Харькове Да а как как
long ago for years  10
давно уже лет 10
probably I came I came to the
наверное я приезжал я приезжал на рынок
Barabashov market in Kharkov and in short I
Барабашова в Харьков и короче
met a girl Well, how we
Познакомился с девушкой Ну как мы у них
bought goods from them and somehow it started yes
товар покупали и как-то так завязалась
when I came to Kharkov to live I have a kiosk here on
да при ехал в Харьков жить у меня тут на
Barabashovo there is a business view
Барабашово киоске есть бизнес виду
yes And what do you talk about here Well judging by the
да А о чём общаетесь тут Ну судя по
symbols you discuss some
символике обсуждаете какие-то
political topics narratives I am
политические темы нарративы меня Меня
more interested yes when I find
больше интересует да я когда нахожу
people from my region yes
людей из моей области да
Belgorod then it is
то Белгородской то вот
so interesting to talk to them
так интересно с ними
and And if it is not a secret can you tell me what is
и А если не секрет можете рассказать как
your
вас
name Andrey Andrey And if my name is
зовут Андрей Андрей А если меня
Alexander and if it is not a secret can you
Александр а ес ли не секрет можете
tell me what is the most
рассказать что самое такое
burning
животрепещущий
[music]
[музыка]
flies in I am like And what are you guys
прилетает я такой А что вам ребята
Uh-huh Well that is, you are interested in the topic only
Угу Ну то есть вам интересна тема только
specifically Retribution Well that
именно вот Возмездие Ну то
is, they were glad that you were flying in and
есть они радовались что вам прилетает и
now you are asking something there is How do
вы теперь спрашиваете что то есть Каково
you feel now because you have also
теперь Вам потому что Вам теперь тоже
been flown in yes
прилетело
And what opinion can be formed about the fact
да А какое мнение Может сложиться о том
that, let's say, you have been flown in They
что допустим вам прилетело Они вам
tell you like Well, you have been flown in like let's let's
говорят типа А ну вот вам прилетело типа
let's do
давайте давайте
what Or let's do those Let's do  zku
что Или давайте те Давайте зку снова
pull out again Why do they, my neighbor was
вытащите Почему они вот у меня сосед был
Sanya Prokhorov, yes, he generally signed up for the
Саня Прохоров да он вообще записался в
Volunteers, signed up for the Volunteers,
Добровольцы записался в Добровольцы
went to war, like, yes, in Kherson,
пошёл на войну типа да в под херсоном
he had everything there with a drone Why did he
ему там дроном
I don’t
всё Зачем он Я не
know Yeah
знаю
And now you, uh, are
Угу А Вы теперь
more happy for Ukraine
ээ больше радуетесь за Украину
and that Ukraine should be like Well, just
и что вот Украина должна каким Ну просто
that Ukraine is against Russia, Russia is
что вот Украина против России Россия
against Ukraine and Ukraine should win this conflict,
против Украины и в этом конфликте должна
I understand correctly
победить Украина я я правильно понимаю
In the sense of Ukraine, Russia is not against
В смысле Украина Россия ж не выт с
Ukraine And with whom Well, that is, the NATO bloc
Украиной А с кем Ну то есть блоком НАТО
with Europe Well, do you still believe that
с европ Ну вы вы верите до сих пор что
Russia is at war with Ukraine I see
Россия воюет с Укра Я же вижу тут в
these NATO instructors here in Kharkov All
Харькове эти натовские инструкторы Все
Americans, British, just darkness oh Wow Well, in
американцы британцы просто тьма ой
fact, in fact
Обалдеть Ну на самом деле на самом деле
Yes, such an opinion is rarely heard, but this is
Да редко такое мнение услы но это
so that with Europe And with NATO,
так чтобы с Европой А с НАТО
probably not NATO, no NATO, this is an abstract
наверное не НАТО нет НАТО это абстракт
NATO itself no longer exists in fact, yes with
НАТО уже само не существует по сути да с
Europe, these are the British Oh okay, NATO does not exist,
европ это же британцы Ой ладно НАТО не
these are the British, the British, where do
существует это британцы британцы где у
we have British instructors here, there are
нас тут британские инструктора
no Americans, the British, and in  that
американцев нет британцы они и в том что
they have a very cunning position Yes, they
у них очень хитрая позиция Да они ж
seem to be democrats, but they have a king,
вроде как демократы но у них король
queen, and they have subjects, they have the right to rule
королева да у них поданные они прав
the world through the Rothschilds, Rottweilers, these Well,
миром через ротшильдов ротвейлеров вот
I get it Well, then let me
этих Ну я понял А хорошо тогда я
rephrase it, are
переформулируйте есть в этом
you against Russia in this confrontation
противостоянии вы против России
or not, yes, yes, well, it's
получается или нет да
very strange And why should I be for it
да ну очень странно А почему я за должен
Well, in my opinion, it's strange to
быть Ну м на мой взгляд странно
betray your homeland I mean, to betray
предавать свою родину В смысле предавать
your homeland My homeland is generally the Soviet Union I
Моя Родина вообще Советский Союз Я
was born in the first year in the Soviet
родился в во первом году в Советском
Union, it was betrayed by Yeltsin, Gorbachev, these
Союзе её предали Ельцин Горбачёв вот эти
Yes, they took it from Moscow, they destroyed my Great
Да из Москвы взяли развалили мою Великую
country I was with Kharkov at the same time, in the same
страну я с Харьковом был в одно в одной
country, it was Great, we launched a man into space,
стране Великой был мы в космос человека
and now
запускали а сейчас
what Well, it turns out that you were born in the
что Ну получается что вы родились в
RSFSR, yes,
РСФСР да
and this is the Russian Soviet
а это Российская Советская
Socialist Federative
социалистическа Федеративная
Socialist Republic Yes, but the
Социалистическая Республика Да вот а но
country was like the Soviet
страна типа у нас была Советский
Union, and then Gorbachev and Yeltsin Yes, they
Союз и потом Горбачёв с Ельциным Да
took it and betrayed it, and no one came out to
взяли и предали и никто не вышел
defend the Soviet Union, everyone said Well,
защищать Советский Союз все сказали Ну
okay, yes And we received a Russian passport
окей да А паспорт российский
with a passport
получили с паспортом
Of course, I have a Russian
Конечно я с российским
passport  Well, that's how it
паспортом Ну так вот
turns out The heir, first of all, is the RSFSR
получается Наследник во-первых РСФСР
And the passport, look at the passport - it's
А паспорт паспорт смотри паспорт - это
just that in Crimea there were also
вообще просто он в Крыму тоже были
Ukrainian passports now Russian
украинские паспорта теперь российские
passports are such a thing Damn it, I don't care at all there
паспорт это такое блин вообще пофиг
will be the European Union here I'll get a European passport
будет тут Евросоюз Европейский паспорт
God, what's the
получу Боже какая
difference Well, okay At least in
разница Ну хорошо По крайней мере в
Russia the Ukrainian language is not banned and in
России украинский язык не запрещают и в
principle no language is banned
принципе никакой язык не запрещают
say look, in our Belgorod
сказать смотрите у нас в Белгородской
region there are a lot of villages that they
области есть куча сёл которые они
speak Ukrainian but they didn't make Ukrainian schools for them
говорят на украинском языке но школы им
but they don't ban them they
делали но не
just
запрещают их просто
closed them at the beginning of the 20th century subjects were studied there
закрыли в начале XX века изучались там
in Ukrainian then they were closed Well, they closed them
предметы на украинском языке потом их
because because because
Ну позакрывали потому что потому что что
we had a policy of Russification
потому что политика русификации у нас
that we should all
была что мы должны все на русском
speak Russian Well, that is, it turns out there was
говорить Ну то есть получается был
some kind of law that prohibits
какой-то закон что запрещают
speaking by closing it you can speak you
говорить закрывая говорить можно
speak in Ukraine Here I am in Kharkov I
говорите в Украине Вот тут я в Харькове
speak Russian at all Nobody
говорю на русском языке мне вообще Никто
prohibits me Well, that is, in Ukraine
запрещает Ну то есть на Укра Украине
now there is no law that in
сейчас не выходит закон о том что в
school They prohibit speaking Russian
школе Запрещают говорить на русском
my child is now in the
языке у меня ребёнок ходит сейчас в
third grade
третий класс
at school Kharkov school number  37
в школе харьковская школа номер 37
comprehensive he speaks Russian I have
общеобразовательная он говорит по-русски
Yeah because my wife she speaks she
меня Угу потому что жена она говорит она
understands Ukrainian But she speaks
украински понимает Но она говорит
Russian she is Russian-speaking from Kharkov
по-русски она русскоязычная из Харькова
Yes I understand Ukrainian I understand but it is
Да я украинский понимаю Понимаю но мне
difficult for me to speak it now
трудно на нём говорить у меня сейчас
many words in Ukrainian already
многие слова на украинском уже
slip through but like and the child we
проскакивают но так типа и ребнок мы
communicate at home in Russian
дома общаемся на русском языке
he reads Pushkin at the school level They
он у меня Пушкина читает на уровне школы
ban the Russian language how can you in U at
Запрещают русский язык как можно на У
all Even even during breaks
вобще Даже даже на переменах общаться
no The thing is that No you are probably
нет Дело в том что Нет вы наверное
confusing something The thing is that we do not have a
что-то путаете Дело в том что у нас не
School a school cannot ban anything in Ukraine
Школа школа не может в Украине что-то
Yes there is a law of Ukraine on
запрещать Да есть закон Украины про
education Yes education he calls about
образование Да образование он называет
osvita about osvita in Ukrainian Yes and
про освиту про освиту по-украински Да и
everything is written there here in each of our
там всё расписано вот у нас в каждой
schools you go and there is a collection of this
школе заходишь и висит сборник этого
law hanging and you read
закона ти и читаешь
everything no I am talking about the fact that a law is being passed
всё нет Я говорю о том что выходит закон
that even during breaks it is forbidden to
именно что даже на переменах запрещено
communicate in Russian at school where is
общаться в школе на русском языке где
this law Show me what
такой закон Покажи какой
law Well I don’t remember the exact number of the law
закон Ну я не помню именно номер закона
I read not the number Well is it a law the
Я читал не номер Ну что это закон
Verkhovna Rada adopted or
Верховная Рада приняла или
not I
что нет
can say  that I did not see that such a
могу сказать что я не видел что такой
law was adopted, everything is prohibited, but such a
закон всё приняли всё запрещено но такой
law was brought up for
закон вынесли на
discussion. Well, that is, it seems to me
обсуждение Ну то есть мне кажется
that in no country in the world, as it
что ни в одной стране мира как
were, in a normal country, in no
бы в нормальной стране вообще ни в одной
country in the world at all, it is simply some kind of
стране мира это просто это какой-то
nonsense to bring such a law up for
нонсенс выносить такой закон на
discussion, even for discussion.
обсуждение просто даже на обсуждение
Despite the fact that there is such a
Несмотря уже то что там принять такой
law to be adopted, the EU, if they adopt such a law, I think
закон ес если примут такой закон Я думаю
that it will be just some kind of horror. That's
что это будет просто какая-то жесть Вот
my question, too. And if they adopt
и у меня вопрос даже такой А если примут
such a law, if it is already being discussed. And if they adopt such a law, what
такой закон если его уже обсуждают А
will you
если примут такой закон что вы будете
do if you Du, if if in
делать если вы Ду е раз если если в
Ukraine I am introducing such a law, what kind of
Украине веду такой закон что за
nonsense, well, now I can
бред хорошо сечас я могу
look at it. I definitely read this and
посмотреть обуда за я точно читал это и
I read This is
я читал Это
for I love reading Ukrainian
нане я обожаю читать украинские
sources, especially Union. It's
источники особенно Union это просто это
just a bunch of
просто кладе каких-то
stand-ups.
стендапов
Let's
давай сейчас
see now. I'm asking directly. In
посмотрим Я прямо так спрашиваю на
Ukraine, they want to ban the
Украине хотят запретить в школах
Russian language in schools. I'll look at the very
русский язык Я посмотрю самые самые
latest ones.
самые
And
А
so 20
так 20
12.03. Well, just like that. I recently read,
12.03 А ну как раз Я недавно читал
and on 12.03 a year ago, a bill was introduced to the Rada on a
а 12.03 д п год в Раду внесли проект о
complete ban on the Russian language in schools.
полном запрете русского языка в школах
Show me
покажи
who.
кто
introduced Now I'll say for a second
внёс Сейчас секунду
here they write that a group of
скажу здесь пишут что группа
Ukrainian parliamentarians
парламентариев украинских
and on Wednesday deputy Maksym Buzhansky
и в среду депутат Максим бужанский
reported
сообщил об
this to
этом
MASI deputy of the Rada Natalia Pipa
МАСИ депутат рады Наталья пипа
registered a bill banning the
зарегистрировал законопроект о запрете
use of at the end of last year
использовани конце прошлого года
Yes, at the end of September last year,
Да в конце сентября прошлого года
deputy of the Rada Natalia Pipa
депутат рады Наталья пипа
registered a bill banning the
зарегистрировала законопроект о запрете
use of any
использования в школах на Украине любого
language other than Ukrainian in schools in Ukraine Wait wait stop stop Did
языка кроме украинского Подожди подожди
I understand correctly, a couple of
стоп стоп Я правильно понял вот пару
days ago they wrote that six months ago she
дней назад написали что полгода она
registered the bill yes yes that
зарегистрировала законопроект да да что
she six months ago eh
она полгода назад э
and that's it, then can we then The text of
а всё а можно тогда можно тогда Текст
this bill finally Come on
этого законопроекта наконец-то Давай да
and discussed it here is the text of the
и обсуждали это вот можно текст
bill what
законопроекта что там
exactly is there so now a second Open like the
конкретно так сейчас секунду Открой типа
text of the bill the website of the Verkhovna Rada
текст законопроекта сайт Верховной Рады
so in the radi registered another
так в ради зарегистрирована очередная
attempt to ban communication in Russian
попытка запретить общение на русском
this is where you even read what are you
языке это где ты вообще читаешь что ты
reading propaganda resource what
читаешь пропагандистский ресурс какой
website what ru ru wait you are
сайт какой ру ру подожди ты российский
reading some Russian website this is a
сайт читаешь какой-то это же
propaganda website they write all sorts of
пропагандистский сайт они там всякий
Bret there Go to the Ukrainian website of the
Брет пишут Зайди на украинский сайт
Verkhovna Rada and look at the bill
Верховной Рады и посмотри законопроект
banning like the Ukrainian language the website of the
запрете типа украинского языка сайт
Verkhovna Rada  Rada and read directly right
Верховной Рады и прочитай прямо напрямую
now so now I'll type in
сейчас так сейчас наберу
Ukraine That is, it turns out that they even
Украин То есть получается детям даже
wanted to ban English for children Yes, so
английский хотели запретить Да так а
and no no no no dailyom But rada go.ua
и нене не не dailyom А вот rada go.ua
website Verkhovna Rada website Yes, find it,
сайт сайт Верховной Рады Да найди вот
write it in the search engine Yes, the law banning the
напиши в поисковике Да закон про запрет
Russian language is the website of the Supreme Council
русского языка сайт верхов рад
Let's take a second now I'm looking just
Давай сейчас секунду я смотрю просто
scrolling I just saw I remember exactly that
листаю Я просто видел Я точно помню что
I saw this
я это видел
on Union
в на Union
Union That's how I was
Union Вот и меня меня такая меня такая
pleased with this information It's
информация порадовал
just that in quotes parade Yeah, I
Просто ну в кавычках парадо Угу
can't find it because it gives me
не могу найти потому что у меня выдаёт
already on the fifth page It gives me
уже на пятой странице у меня выдаёт
only So listen Well, look, I think that
только Так слушай Ну смотри я думаю что
if half a year ago there was such a
если пол полгода назад был такой
bill, it's already been stolen Everything
законопроект его уже растащили Прямо всё
And so only some Russian
А так только какие-то русские
propaganda resources Well, damn, this is not
пропагандистские ресурсы Ну блин ну это
serious, really, you could have given me Putin's words
аж несерьёзно правда ты бы мне ещё слова
No, I don't read any direct ones Well,
Нет я я не читаю какие-то там прямые Ну
that is, I don't read Russian or
то есть я не читаю не российские не ни
any media in the world at all Well, that is,
какие-либо СМИ вообще в мире ну то есть
some journalists, why not Well, so
каких-то журналистов пому что Ну так
find, find, find it  oh really damn it
найди найди найди это ж реально блин это
Look it's real now Maybe we have
Смотри это реально сейчас Возможно у нас
such a terrible thing they want I would
такое страшное хотят я сейчас я бы
raise the question now yes What What kind of
поднимал сейчас вопрос да Что Что за
nonsense is being done Let's even be
бред какой-то делается Давай аж
interesting
интересно
so and ryadovka is normal so ryadovka
так а рядовка это нормально так рядовка
is your propaganda Telegram
- это же ваш пропагандистский Telegram
channel Russian ryadovka From the Ministry of
канал российский рядовка От Министерства
Defense of the Russian Federation I don't
обороны Российской Федерации я не в
know imagine I don't know there this this is a
курсе представляете я не в курсе там
link like a
этот это звен типа
journalist I don't know really it
журналист я не в курсе правда
turns out That's our
оказывается Вот это наш
propaganda I just see
пропагандистский Я просто вижу
propaganda when I read there Kru
пропагандистский когда я читаю там кру
TV Zvezda that's what I understand Propaganda
ТВ Звезда это я понимаю Пропаганда
ryadovka is From the Ministry of Defense
рядовка - это От Министерства обороны
newspaper ro that's what I understand let's go further
газета ро это я понимаю давай дальше вот
and I would find something like there Michael
а я бы нашёл что-нибудь типа там Майкл
Naki or something else like that generally
Наки или ещё что-нибудь такое вообще
officially Let's make it official if there
официально Давайте официальное вот если
is a bill for this Yes then it
есть за это же законопроект Да значит он
is on the website of the Verkhovna Rada Well it's
есть да на сайте Верховной Рады Ну это ж
easy to
просто
find And what kind of website is it
найти А как какой сайт как это
called the Supreme Rada website rada
называется верховный сайт рады rada
go.ua so
go.ua так
Now
Сейчас
we'll see not from me it's unlikely to issue And
посмотрим не у меня вряд ли выдаст А у
your Roskomnadzor may have
вас Роскомнадзор его может
banned it Well yes we have many of which What sa
забанил Ну да у нас много каких Какие са
and why why is this website  Ukrainian
а почему почему это сайт украинского
parliament banned Russian
парламента забанил русском
supervision Well, it fights propaganda the same way, yes I
надзор Ну борется с пропагандой такой же
mean Propaganda if this is a site where
да В смысле Пропаганда если это сайт где
laws and
законы и
bills And can you While you are
законопроекты А можете Вот пока пока
looking Yes, while you are looking, you can name at least
ищете Да пока ищете можете назвать хотя
5 million Ukrainians live in Russia
бы вот в России живёт 5 млн украинцев
so at least you can name at least one
так как минимум можете назвать хоть одну
Ukrainian school that speaks Ukrainian
украинскую школу украиноязычный
Well, look, in Moscow, you can name
Ну вот смотрите в Москве можете назвать
there Belgorod region, in Kursk, at least
там Белгородской области в Курской хоть
somewhere in Khanty Mansiysk Okrug there are
где-нибудь ханте Мансийский округ там
a lot of Ukrainians Yes, the Far East I think
куча украинцев Да Дальний Восток Я думаю
that in those regions where it is necessary I
что в тех регионах где это необходимо Я
mean, let's say we have Tatarstan and
что допустим вот у нас есть Татарстан и
in Tatarstan, somewhere 50% of the population
в Татарстане э где-то 50% населения
speaks the Tatar language and this
говорит на татарском языке и это
population needs to be taught the
население нуждается в обучении
Tatar language So wait again
татарского языка Так подождите ещё раз
this is in this region Yes, maybe Now a
это в этом регионе Да може Сейчас
second and in this region there are schools
секунду и в этом регионе есть есть школы
everything I understand I understand the counterargument,
всё я конт я понял контраргумент
look, you have where where in
смотрите у вас есть там где там где в
these regions they need, deceive,
этих регионах нуждаются обманывайте
deceive, look Let's see,
обманывайте смотрите Давайте посмотрим в
about 3 million Kazakhs live in Russia, not some
России живёт около 3 млв казахов не
who came from Kazakhstan but who have
которые приехали из Казахстана а которые
lived since time immemorial Astrakhan region
жили из покон веков Астраханская область
Orenburg region Omsk region Yes,
Оренбургская область Омская область Да
in some areas they are a third of the
вот в некоторых районах они там треть
population there like Show me at least one
населения типа Покажите мне хоть одну
ChNU school in the Orenburg region or in
ЧНУ школу в Оренбургской области или в
Astrakhan there is simply no need for this How is there
Астрахан просто в этом нет нужды Как это
no need Well, let's say there is a
нет нужды Ну допустим есть
need for such national regions where
нужда таких национальных регионов где
people speak Bashkartastan Let's say the
люди говорят башкартастан Давайте
Republic of Bashkartastan at least one at least one
республика башкартастан хоть одну хоть
school in the Bashkir language
одну школу на башкирском языке
show in the Bashkir language Yes, at least
покажите на башкирском языке Да хоть
one school in Bashkortostan in which they
одну школу в Башкортостане в котором на
study subjects in the Bashkir language Well, it
башкирском языке изучают предме Ну
turns out If they studied the Bashkir language,
получается Если бы башкирский язык
then the Bashkir language would have already disappeared
изучали то башкирский язык уже бы исчез
again again No, look, people
ещё раз ещё раз Нет смотрите э люди себе
say to themselves there at home yes, but at school for some reason
говорят там дома да а в школе почему-то
in Russian physics in Russian mathematics
на русском физика на русском математика
in Russian history in Russian
на русском история на русском
why Show me really at least
почему Покажите мне вот реально хоть
one school with the study of all subjects
одну школу э с изучением всех предметов
in the Bashkir language in
на башкирском языке в
Bashkortostan or in Buryatia in the Buryat
Башкортостане или в Бурятии на бурятском
language Yeah, okay Now for a second I can
языке Угу хорошо Сейчас секунду я могу
say that in Russia there are also Tai people
сказать что в России есть ещё Тай народ
like the Ubykhs Ubykhs I know my grandfather is an Ubykh
как убыхи убыхи я знаю у меня дед убых
that's why  ubs schools No these are Circassians this is a
вот почему убс школы Нет это черкесы это
check Why school so here I am because
чеке Почему школа так вот я потому что
Russia Yes it prohibits in the Caucasus my
Россия Да запрещает на Кавказе у меня
grandfather is Ubykh By the way my grandfather is Ubykh yes a ba
дед убых Кстати у меня дед убых да а ба
And where is the indigenous population of Uy in the Caucasus And
А где коренное население уы на Кавказе А
my grandmother is from PSU I am half
бабушка у меня из псу я наполовину
Circassian You are very good that you
черкес Вы очень хорошо что вы это
said this yes this Krasnodar
сказали да вот этот Краснодарский
kva Sochi all sorts Yes these are ALL Circassian
ква Сочи всякие Да это ВС черкесские
names so once
названия так ещ
again fail once again once again
раз прова ещ раз ещ
look not in Adygea or in
раз вот смотрите ни в Адыгее ни в
Karachay-Cherkessia Kabardino-Balkaria
Карачаево Черкесии Кабардино Балкарии
even in those enclaves of our Circassians
даже в тех анклава наших черкесских
which Russia left Yes there is no study
которые Россия оставила Да нету изучения
in Circassian languages ​​there is no in
на черкесских языках нету на
Adyghe there is no
адыгском нету
Ubykh There is an Adyghe language Russia
убыхский Есть адыгский язык Россия
look we are all these Circassians Yes we are
смотрите мы все вот эти черкесы Да мы
Adyghe here in Karachay-Cherkessia
Адыги вот в карачаево-черкессии
Kabardino-Balkaria in Adygea Yes in the
Кабардино Балкарии в Адыгеи Да в
Krasnodar Territory it is all one
Краснодарском крае это всё один
Circassian Ethnicity here in the Adyghe language
Черкесский Этнос вот на адыгском языке
which  speaks in no school
который разговаривает во ни одной школы
in Adyghe there is no school in
на адыгском языке нет ни одной школы на
Buryat there is no school there is no well go ahead and
бурятском нет ни одной школы нету ну
search Find me at least one school in
давай ищи Найди мне хоть одну школу на
Buryat in Bar
бурятском языке на на барском
Let's go in Mari I just don't understand
Давай на марийском Я просто не понимаю А
What is the actual problem Wait wait stop stop
в чём в чём собственно проблема Подожди
stop you just told me, a
подожди стоп стоп стоп ты мне только
Russian who has lived
что россиянину который живёт десяток лет
in Ukraine for ten years, about some kind of
в Украине рассказываешь про там какое-то
oppression And so on My child is in the
Утес нение И так дальше Мой ребёнок в
third grade and goes to a Ukrainian school
третьем классе ходит в украинскую школу
and speaks Russian there his wife speaks
и говорит по-русски там жена общается
Russian she is Ukrainian but Russian speaking
по-русски она украинка но русскоязычная
I am a woman who lives in Kharkov
я руки который живу в Харькове
Yes I speak Russian no one has ever
Да я общаюсь по-русски мне никто никогда
done anything to me And you tell me there are
ничего не сделал И ты мне говоришь там
schools there They forbid And so on so tell me
школы Запрещают И так дальше так скажи
where in Russia do we have at least one school yes In
где у нас в России Хоть одна школа да На
these national languages ​​Show me
вот этих на национальных языках Покажи в
at least one school in the Republic of Bashkartastan
Республике башкартастан хоть одну школу
I have studied these
нету Я изучал эти
issues the Kazakhs have no schools the Buryats have
вопросы у казахов нету школ у бурятов
no schools the Mari have no schools all
нету школ у марийцев нету школ все
were still under Lenin  Lenin also had
при Ленине ещё были при Ленине ещё были
national schools then op Well, that is, in
национальные школы потом оп Ну то есть в
Russia there is some law that,
России существует какой-то закон о том
uh, it is forbidden to speak any
ээ Запрещают говорить на каком-либо
language, so look, look Yes, in Russia there
языке значит смотри смотри Да в России
is a law, so even before that, uh,
существует закон значит ещё до этого э
10 years ago, no, no, 10-15 years ago Yes, there
лет 10 назад не не 10-15 лет назад Да
were some schools that still
были некоторые школы ещё оставались с
taught in the Bashkir language Yes,
преподаванием на башкирском языке Да
some, yes, a law was passed Yes, there was some that would
некоторые да вышел закон Да какой-то был
transfer everything to Russian as the language of
что переводить все на русский язык
instruction for their integration blah-blah-blah
обучения для интеграции их бла-бла-бла
but under Putin there is not a single school
вот при Путине и ни одной школы не
left, really, look Well, it's
осталось реально вот посмотри Ну это ж
just for you, just to my face and
просто тебе ж просто мне в лицо и
say Look I googled in Buryat there is a
сказать Смотри Я на гуглил в буряти есть
school where physics is studied in Buryat,
вот школа физика на бурятском изучается
mathematics is taught there in Buryat Yes, in
там математика на бурятском Да в
Tatarstan, in Chuvashia, in short, and so on
Татарстане в чувашие короче и всё и так
Further, there is none in all of these
Дальше нету во всех во всех этих
republics, there is only the national
республиках есть только национальный
language,
язык
there are two lessons a
там два урока в
week and that's it
неделю и
I asked a question in Russia there
всё нет Я же вопрос задал в России
is a law that prohibits
существует закон который запрещает
studying the language again, look I am
изучать язык ещё раз смотрите Я сейчас
not delving into it now
не вдающиеся
Why is this Well, it seems to me because of
Почему это Ну мне кажется из-за
necessity, no, why in Why  there
необходимости нет почему в Почему в
is a national school in Chechnya Why
Чечне есть национальная школа Почему
Which Show no in Chechnya there is no school in Chechnya
Какая Покажи нету в Чечне нету в Чечне
in which Physics and mathematics are in
школы в которой Физика и математика на
Chechen No
чеченском Нет
why why in Crimea there is in In what
почему почему в Крыму есть на На каком
language in Dagestan in school in what language
языке в Дагестане в школе на каком языке
look if you say no you you are deceiving
смотри если ты говори нет ты ты обману
you are deceiving now Yes look you
ешь ты обману ешь сейчас Да смотри ты
this is just a lie Tell me in Dagestan
это просто брехня Назови мне в Дагестане
in what language there is a national school
на каком языке национальная школа
yes I have not studied all the schools but they are
есть да я я же не изучал все школы но
all there Avars Dargins there is no Dagestani language
все там есть аварцы даргинцы
Look you there is no
дагестанского языка нет Смотри ты нет
Dagestani language there is no Dagestani
дагестанского языка нет дагестанского
people in Dagestan Avars Kumyks
народа в Дагестане живут аварцы кумыки
Darkin Tabasarans Laks Lezgins And so
даркин табасаранцы лакцы лезгины И так
on In what language is there a
дальше На каком хоть одном языке ихнем
school here is the largest from us
есть школа вот самый большой от нас
Dagestan Avars are there in the Avar language
Дагестана аварцы есть на аварском языке
At least
Хоть
one Well no no don't worry no let's
одна Ну нету нету не мучайся нет
see
посмотрим
if there are
ели
national national schools in
национальные национальные школы в
Dagestan then just go to the website of this
Дагестане то просто зайди на сайт этой
school directly and look Yes in  There
школы прямо и посмотри Да в Дагестане
are schools in Dagestan where they study national
есть школы где изучают национальные
traditions and culture, they study
традиции и культуру во изучают
national traditions of culture, that is,
национальные традиции культуры то есть
they All study in Russian, but they
они Все учатся на русском языке но у них
have lessons in National Di, look, kids,
есть уроки Националь ди смотрите детки
you had such dances, you had
вот у вас были такие танцы у вас были
such costumes and everything, and all the teaching is in
такие костюмы и всё А всё обучение на
Russian
русском
Well, just Interesting, well, you yourself, you yourself
языке Да ну просто Интере ну ты сам ты
read it correctly You yourself
же сам прочитал правильно Ты же сам
read it, yes, in schools where they study
прочитал да в школа в которых изучают
national culture, that is,
национальную культуру то есть вводится
one lesson is introduced, it is called the history of the native
один урок называется там история родного
land or the history of the republic and that's all, here are the
края или там история республики и всё
traditions, at the same time According to Russian
традиции при этом Согласно российскому
law, the
законода
study of national languages ​​cannot be
изу национальных языков не может
carried out to the detriment of the study of
още осуществляться в ущерб изучение
Russian as the state language. That
русского языка как государственного Вот
is, the Russian language is still in all
то есть русский язык всё-таки во всех
schools Yes, as the state language, the most
школах Да как государственный самое
important thing is that the national language cannot be
главное что национальный язык не может
carried out to the detriment of Russian Yes, that
осуществляться в ущерб ущерб русскому да
is, yes, that is, mathematics, physics and
то есть да то есть математику физику и
all subjects are taught in
все предметы учат на
Russian Yes, why not,
русском Да почему бы нет
you now you now confirmed yes, that
ты сейчас ты сейчас подтвердил да то что
in what year the rating of the best schools of the
на че год в рейтинг лучших школ
Republic of Dagestan included republican schools, everything, everything,
Республики Дастан вошли республиканские
so what difference does it make, they are all in
всё всё так какая разница это они все на
Russian, everything, they are all in Russian
русском языке всё они все на русском
Yes, you yourself confirmed it Yes, that they
языке Да ты сам же это подтвердил Да что
cannot be to the detriment Because if
не могут в ущерб Потому что если изучают
they study in a language other than Russian  language yes then it is
они на не русском языке да тогда это
detrimental to Russian here you even
идёт ущерб русском вот тебе даже прям ты
gave an example yourself that is look question
сам привёл пример то есть смотри вопрос
interesting yes
интересно да
that Russia is a
что в России
multinational country It has
многонациональная страна В ней есть
ethnic Republics even yes it is a
этнические Республики даже да это
Federation but for some reason
Федерация но почему-то
in all regions including even in these
во всех регионах в том числе даже в этих
ethnic Yes republics national
этнических Да республик национальных
republics there is not a single stupidly not a single
республиках нету ни одной тупо ни одной
school we are not even talking about
школы мы уже не говорим даже про
universities where education is conducted
университеты в которое образование идёт
in the native language you know how they do everything they
на родном языке знаешь как им делают всё
teach in Russian and they include their native language
учат на русском а родной язык им
Nede As a native language and everything so it is
включают Неде Как родной язык и всё так
not here simply The Big Difference is
нет здесь просто Большая Разница в том
that in Russia not a single language is banned And
что в России ни один язык не запрещают А
in Ukraine They ban well look in in
на Украине Запрещают хоро смотри в в
Russia They ban the Ukrainian language
России Запрещают украинский язык
look at the Ukrainian library in Moscow they
посмотри украинскую библиотеку в Москве
closed the Ukrainian library in Moscow
закрыли в Москве украинскую библиотеку
Yes there was Ukrainian Yes the Ukrainian
Да была украинская Да украинская
diaspora made a Ukrainian library Yes
диаспора делала украинскую библиотеку Да
Why did they close the Ukrainian library in
Почему закрыли украинскую библиотеку в
Moscow Maybe there was some kind of propagandist there
Москве Может там пропагандист какая-то
literature it is unlikely they would close it
была литература вряд ли бы закрыли ещё
again Well literature Well no look if
раз Ну литература Ну нет смотри е если
if
если
literature Yes why Yes why when to the
литература Да почему Да почему когда к
monument to the forest Why to the monument to the forest
памятнику ле Почему к памятнику лес
Ukrainian woman when people brought flowers  and they
Украинке когда люди приносили цветы и их
were arrested there is a street Lesi Ukrainka
арестовывали есть улица Леси Украины
Look this is left from the Soviet Union
Смотри это от Советского Союза осталось
Yes why now when Why to the
Да почему сейчас когда Почему к
monument of Ukrainka forest when they bring
памятнику лес Украинки когда приносят
flowers why people were arrested
цветы почему людей арестовывали
why people are arrested I don't
почему людей арестовывают я не
believe on a bender
вири
pris on a bender So everything yes google it
загуло прис загули Так всё да загугли
now they detained near the monument of
вот сейчас задержали возле памятника
Lesi Ukrainka right now they gave or
Леси Украинки прямо сейчас давали или
detained Well they detained Yes and they took them to the police station So now come on
задержали Ну задержали Да и в ментовку
come on And when was it they
давай А когда это
arrested near the monument they detained
было арестовали у памятника задержали
so monument of whom Lesi
так памятника кого Леси
Ukrainka Yes I'm interested that so the
Украинки Да мне интересно что так
police we read so in St. Petersburg they
полиция читаем так в Петербурге
detained about 20 people in Moscow
задержали около 20 человек в Москве
and in St. Petersburg about 20 people in Moscow
а в Петербурге около 20 человек в Москве
seven on some of the composition anti-covid
семь на некоторых соста антиковидные
protocols and acts of disobedience to the police
протоколы и акты неповиновения полиции
so and according to
так и по
what it was in the twenty-third
какому это было в двадцать третьем
year during
году во время
covid further what covid d Three year
ковида дальше какой ковид д Трей год
Listen well already its in full swing covid
Слушай ну уже сво шло полным ходом ковид
and so its started Right during
та так сво началось Прямо во время
covid its now in d vto year And this is
ковида сво на сечас в д втом году А это
already twenty Three Yes  so in the twenty-third
уже дцать Трей Да так в двадцать третьем
year your not yet covid has not ended yet that
году сво ещё не ковид ещё не закончился
and not ended Come on come on look So this is how Well
то а не закончился Давай давай смотри
I see this was in the
Значит так Ну я смотрю так это в
twenty-third year Well then they were
двадцать третьем году было Ну то
detained for flowers near the monument to
задерживали за цветы возле памятника
Lesya Ukrainka and they were only given a fine
Леси Украинки та им влупил только штраф
under covid and everything happened again again
по по ковиду и всё вышло ещё раз ещё раз
that is they were detained for uh the fact that they
то есть их задержали за ээ то что они
came to the monument to Lesya Ukrainka with
пришли к памятнику Леси Украинки с
flowers Did I understand correctly No under covid that's
цветами Я правильно понял Нет по ковиду
right them come on so they were detained for the
правильно их давай так их задержали за
fact that they came in the twenty-
то что они без маски пришли в двадцать
third year to the monument to Lesya Ukrainka without a mask yes they were
третьем году к памятнику лес Украинки да
detained under covid yes What does it
задержали по ковиду да Что
mean that under covid d Three
значит что по ковиду д Трей
years Well that is to say there was what is it
год Ну то есть
called there was a
называется был
quarantine they came during the quarantine to the
карантин они пришли во время карантина к
monument and they were detained during the quarantine
памятнику и их задержали во время
at the monument and here you don't need to
карантина у памятника и тут не нужно
confuse umt detained during the quarantine
путать умт задержали во время карантина
at the monument stop stop stop I
у памятника стоп стоп стоп я правильно
understand correctly that in the twenty-third year
понимаю что в двадцать третьем году у
you had a quarantine and it was forbidden what to
вас был карантин и нельзя было что
do to walk without a mask in the twenty-
делать ходить без маски в двадцать
third year you walked in
третьем году вы ходили в
masks Yes there was a law again you are
масках Да был закон ещё раз ты вот на
seriously saying now that  in
полном серьёзе сейчас говоришь что в
2023 you wore
двадцать третьем году вы ходили в
masks Yes but they couldn't have
масках Да но их не могли бы их не могли
fined them without a law if there is no
бы оштрафовать без закона вот если
law then they couldn't have Or maybe
закона нет то есть их не могли бы А може
you can open this video and watch
можешь открыть это видео и посмотреть
or police officers in covid masks 2 yes
или полицейские в масках ковидных 2 да
maybe there were police officers without masks Yeah
возможно были и полицейские без Маск Ага
So do I understand correctly that in
То есть я правильно понимаю что двадцать
2023 yes police officers without masks all the
третий год да полицейские без масок все
people on the street without masks in general stupidly everyone without masks
люди на улице без масок вообще тупо все
Yes I'll now For the sake of curiosity I'll
без масок Да я сейчас Ради любопытства
even look at this photo so
даже посмотрю это фото так
detention at the monument so there is a video of
задержание у у памятника так там видео
Ukrainian foxes
есть лиси Украинки
Yes by the way there is a
Да кстати есть
video of
видео
here is a police officer without masks what covid
по вот полицейский без масок какой ковид
so
так
20 No this is not that video this is already
20 Нет это это не то видео это это уже
some twenty-fifth
какого-то двадцать пятого
year It seems to me that you
года Мне кажется что вы жалко
look pathetic attempts to justify covid
выглядите попытки оправдать ковид
Yes no why I just know that in Russia the
Да нет почему я просто знаю что в России
law is in effect that's
действует закон вот и
all in the video video Open you ignore the video video
всё виде видео видео Открой пропускаете
Open wait
мимо ушей видео видео Открой подожди
video OTK No no you're running away you're running away you
видео ОТК Нет нет ты убегаешь ты
can't
убегаешь ты убегаешь не
convince Come on come on look look or
убе Давай давай смотри смотри или
were the police
полиция была
in  some one and you miss the
вде какой-то один а вы пропускаете мимо
most important thing that I'm saying is that in
ушей самое главное что я говорю что в
Russia they don't ban any language and in
России не запрещают ни один язык а на
Ukraine they ban it again and again not a
Украине Запрещают ещё раз ещё раз ни
single one we don't have a ban No, come on and no more no no no Come on you se
одного у нас запрета Нет давай и больше
You're
нет нет нет нет Давай ты се Ты сейчас
watching now yes yes and I showed you that
смотришь да да и я тебе показал что у
you don't have a single school yes in
вас нету ни одной школы да на
national languages ​​What do you Ban they
национальных языках Что у вас Запрещают
closed your Ukrainian library Yes
у вас закрыли украинскую библиотеку Да
which you had they took and they
которая была у вас взяли и это
detain people who go to the
и задерживают людей которые к памятнику
Lesya Ukrainka monument lust Come on fla Come on you found a
Леси Украинки похот Давай фла Давай ты
video come on find a video opened
нашл видео давай находи видео открыл
English and so on opened a video
английский и так далее открыл видео у
we don't
нас не
ban So now look come on
запрещают Так теперь смотри давай давай
whose year the police detained Danil
чей год полиция задержала Данила
Vershinin near the Lesya Ukrainka monument it's been
Вершинина возле памятника Леси Украинки
a year or so maybe yes Now I see
уже че год не было может да Сейчас вижу
how you are simply breaking into the Central Committee everyone everything everything everything blew up blew up yes yes yes that is
как ты ЦК просто ломятся все всё всё всё
look come on so then you and I are
смотри давай так значит мы с тобой
putting an end to the topic where they oppress language
ставим точку в теме где притесняют язык
in Russia they oppress all languages ​​except
в России притесняют все язы кроме
Russian they oppress we don't have
русского притесняют нет у нас закона
such a law  prites look again at you Yes,
такого притес ещё раз смотри у вас Да
according to the law, they will tell you Covid, they
тебе по закону скажут ковид тебе ещё
will come up with something else for you, there are no national schools,
что-то придумает национальных школ нету
no, it's true, yes, there are national schools, there
нету правда да есть национальные школы
are national schools in Crimea, look,
вон в Крыму есть национальны смотри
how many, let's do it How many Russians are in Ukraine,
сколько давай так Сколько в Украине ру
according to the census, less than
русского населения по переписи меньше
10% Well, the Russian language is banned, wait,
10% Ну и запрещён русский язык подожди
according to the census, less than 10% of non-Russians in Russia are not
по переписи меньше 10% в России не
Russians, a
русских не русских
quarter Tell me at least one non-
четверть Скажи мне хоть одну нерусскую
Russian school, no such thing Well, there simply is no such thing, a non-Russian school, show me at least one Yes, any
нерусскую школу покажи хоть одну Да
school, I'm in Crimea, any school, no,
любая школа вот я в Крыму любую школу
look, Crimea, Crimea is an
нет смотри Крым Крым - это
occupied territory And
оккупированная территория Да и там живут
citizens of Ukraine live there And that's why Russia is there,
граждане Украины Да и поэтому Россия там
yes, it should show what's there, and so on, and then it's not clear, and
есть вот и так дальше и то непонятно и
show me at least one,
покажи да покажи мне хоть одну вот
now in Crimea By the way, yes, in the first
сейчас в Крыму Кстати да вот в первые
years there were still languages, so
годы ещё были языке значит
give me at least one school in K, which is
пожи мне хоть одну школу в к которая
now completely in Ukrainian,
сейчас полностью на украинском языке
several schools in Moscow, in Bashkiria, in the
несколько школ в Москве в Башкирии в
Belgorod region and the Krasnodar
Белгородской области и Краснодарском
region, what are Bashkirs and Ukrainian schools in Moscow Come
крае что в Москве башкири украинских
on in, now we're opening the website of
школ Давай заходи сейчас открываем сайт
this school  come on find me this school in
этой школы давай найди мне эту школу в
Moscow
Москве
come on a Ukrainian school in Moscow Find
Давай украинскую школу в Москве Найди
me let's go to its website and see yes
мне зайдём на её сайт и посмотрим да
If this school is on the website in
Если же есть эта школа на сайте
Ukrainian Yes there
по-украински Да там
And so on Let's
И так дальше Давай сейчас
see now well here I say again that in
посмотрим ну здесь ещё раз говорю что в
Russia there is no law Yes yes yes there is
России не существует закона Да да да о
simply no ban on other languages
запрете других языков просто не
How
существует Как
can you
можно
talk in the Duma about banning conversations
рассуждать в Думе о запрете разговоров
during breaks in Russian Now come on come on
на переменах на русском языке Вот это
find me here you
давай давай давай найди мне вот ты
said I'm catching you on your
сказал Я тебя ловлю на твоей
[music]
[музыка]
lying
брехнею
school number 56 named after Academician Legasov
школа номер 56 имени Академика легасова
By the way I'm watching yes news for here I just
Вот кстати я смотрю да новости за вот я
went and typed in a Ukrainian school in Moscow yes
взял и вбил украинская школа в Москве да
there and the Russian ambassador to Ukraine Zurabov has
там вот и посол России в Украине зурабов
been saying for the eleventh year there will be
ещё одиннадцатый год говорил украинской
no Ukrainian school in Moscow
школы в Москве не
writes Well just fine Well that is, let's
будет пишет Ну просто хорошо Ну то есть
say I want to study the Ukrainian language
допустим я хочу изучать украинский язык
living in Moscow Just why do I need
проживая в Москве Просто зачем мне я на
it again Well look Well if a Russian
нём ещё раз Ну смотрите Ну если русскому
who lives in Kharkov
который проживает в Харькове зачем-то
needs Russian for some reason Why can't a Ukrainian who
нужен русский Да почему украинцу который
lives in Moscow have
проживает в Москве не может быть
Ukrainian Why  a Tatar who
украинский Почему татарину который
lives in Moscow does not need Tatar
проживает в Москве не нужен татарский
Why Bashkort Yes, who lives in
Почему башкорт Да который проживает в
Bashkortostan does not need
Башкортостане не нужен
Bashkir Well, probably because he can
башкирский Ну наверное потому что он его
practically not use it anywhere
не практически нигде не может применить
again, that is, look at me, you
ещё раз то есть смотри ты мне ты мне
told me before that there is, there is, there is, and
говорил до этого что ээ есть есть есть а
now you say that there is not because it is
теперь говоришь что нету потому что он
not needed So it does
не нужен То вс-таки
exist or were you lying that there
есть или ты обманывал что
is Why did I lie, don’t run away, don’t run away, don’t run away
есть Почему я обманывал не убегай не
Oh, don’t run away, don’t hang out
убегай не убегай Ой не убегай не Зависай
If you didn’t lie Show me you said with
Если ты не обманывал Покажи ты сказал
your mouth that there are two
своим ртом что в Москве есть две
Ukrainian schools in Moscow there are also Find me at least
украинских школы там ещё Найди мне хоть
one Ukrainian school in Moscow right
одну украинскую школу в Москве мы прямо
now, we’ll go to this site, I’ll look and
сейчас зайдём на этот сайт я посмотрю и
say yes You were right it’s just that now
скажу да Ты был прав этож просто сейчас
each school has its own site, each one, even some
каждая школа свой сайт каждая даже блин
kind of district school Now we’ll
какая-то Сейчас
see not I just don’t understand, well, it’s
посмотрим не я просто не понимаю ну
just logical I Let’s find it first
просто логически я Давай сначала найдём
and then we’ll be able to logically understand well Were there any
и тогда сможем логически понять хорошо
schools? Let’s find them, we’ll find ones
Ели Ели школы Давай найдём найдём
that
которые
study everything completely in Chinese Come on,
изучают полностью всё на китайском языке
come on  hiring un bym
Давай давай найм ун
maybe Well just a question why
бым может быть Ну просто вопрос зачем
just look we just find a
просто смотри мы просто находим
Ukrainian school and if we close the
украинскую школу а если и закрываем
questions I kind of admit Yes that there is a school that
вопросы я типа признаю Да что школа есть
fully teaches subjects in the Papuan
ко полностью ведёт предметы на папуас
language once again you yes you don't have 5 million
языке ещё раз у вас да у вас нету 5 млн
Chinese you don't have 5 million Papuans You
китайцев у вас нет 5 млн папуасов У вас
have 5 million Ukrainians Yes who, by the way,
есть 5 млн украинцев Да которые причём э
live there
живут Там давным-давно
They haven't arrived there for a long time some migrants yes
они не приехали какие-то мигранты да у
you have a Bashkortostan living Yes you have now equated the
вас живёт башкорт Да ты приравнял сейчас
residents of the national republics with
жителей национальных республик к
some Papuans Yes who live somewhere
каким-то папуаса Да которые живут где-то
in Papua New Guinea are you ready to
в Папуа Новой Гвинеи ты готов Вот так
say that the residents of the national
сказать что жители национальных
republics for example that Ramzan
республик например что вот Рамзан
Kadyrov is a Papuan Yes that Yevkurov is a Papuan that the
Кадыров папуас Да что Евкуров папуас что
president of Bashkortostan for the sake of Khabib is a
президент Башкортостана ради хабиров
Papuan are you ready to say that And how are the
папуас ты готов так сказать А чем
Papuans worse than other people No well
папуасы хуже другого народа Не ну они
they just live there somewhere in No I'm
просто они живут там где-то вной гне
ready for sza pa And how are the Papuans worse No they are
готов сза па А чем папуасы хуже Нет они
not worse They just don't live in Russia they
не хуже Они просто не в России живут они
live there are you ready to talk about this  you are
живут там ты готов про это и говорю ты
you ready to say yes there are no Easter schools
ты готов сказать да паски школ нет
because they are not needed Are you ready to
потому что они не нужны Вот ты готов
say yes that Bashkor Buryats Chechens and
сказать да что башкор буряты чеченцы и
all the rest Yes you are equating them in terms of
все остальные Да ты их в плане
education
образования
and language Well their
приравнивание и язык Ну ихний
national language you are attached to Chinese and
национальный язык ты Прив к китайскому и
Pus language
пусскому языку
Understand No first of all I said that in Chen in
Поня Нет во-первых я сказал что в чене в
Chechnya there are schools where they study the
Чечне существуют школы где изучают
Chechen language again no no no
чеченский язык ещё раз нет нет нет
wrong look No the Chechen language is studied
неправильно смотри Нет чеченский язык
Bashkor there is not a single Chinese language in
башкор китайского языка ни одного в
Chechnya there is not a single school where all
Чечне нет ни одной школы в котором всё
teaching is conducted in the Chechen language not a
преподавание ведётся на чеченском языке
single one that Chechen is studied Yes
ни одной то что чеченский изучают Да
Bashkor is studied twice a week And so
башкор изучают два раза в неделю А а так
everything is in Russian in Russian It's very simple
всё на русском на русском Очень просто
come on we don't run away yet you want to run away now
давай мы ещё не убегай ты сейчас хочешь
but we must find this Great
убежать но мы должны найти эту Великую
school there are two of them find at least one in
школу их там две найди хотя бы одну в
Moscow that is in Ukra They ban the
Москве которая на Укра Запрещают
Ukrainian language not in the Ukrainian language
украинский язык не на украинском языке
Find me a school in Moscow you said either
Найди мне школу в Москве ты сказал либо
Admit that it doesn't
Признай что её
exist no I can't admit I just don't
нету не я не могу признать Я просто не
know well come on well  find Well, it's simple
знаю ну давай ну найди Ну это ж просто
Well, look Russia,
Ну смотри Россия
I'll
я
show you, I can just tell you from
покажи я я просто могу сказать по
statistics I've seen a bunch of videos
статистике Я видел кучу видео
where Ukrainians Yes, Ukrainians Yes, look,
где украинцы Да украинцы Да смотри
Ukrainians are not Ukrainians Tell me Look, you're
украинцы не украинцы Скажи мне Смотри ты
running away, I'll drive you around with your face
убегаешь я тебя Буду возить твоим лицом
Until you get tired or don't
по твоему Да пока ты не устанешь либо не
admit it,
призна
show me Or maybe you'll show me
ты показуй мне Либо ты мне может
I'll turn off the sound when I
покажешь я тебе отключаю звук когда я
talk to you Yes, you'll run away now, you'll run away, you
тебе говорю Да ты сейчас убежишь ты
'll spin, spin and
убежишь ты будешь крутить крутить и
merge Yes, you're delaying find a school in
сольётся Да ты оттягивает найди школу в
Moscow that's in Ukrainian
Москве которая на украинском языке
Come on No, I'll ask you to find find a school
Давай Нет я я попрошу найти найди школу
in Moscow in Ukrainian find me
в Москве на украинском языке найди мне
Look, you told your p that there
Смотри ты сказал своим р том что в
is a school in Moscow with Ukrainian as the language of
Москве есть школа с украинским языком
instruction, show me
обучения покажи
I even named the number I even named
Я же даже номер Назвал
which one Yes, I don't remember anymore I watched That's what
какой Да я уже не помню я смотрел Вот
Baby, well, this is not funny anymore You're just
что Малыш ну это уже не смешно Ты так ты
saying that with covid, yes, it's shameful, it's
скажем с ковидом просто да позорно
shameful She was detained because of covid, in short
позорно это Её изза ковида короче
And now even further Come on,
задержали А теперь ещё дальше
they issued a fine for covid Look,
Давай штраф выписали по ковиду смотри Ну
this is very  there is just now Google
это же очень просто есть сейчас Google
yes there is Yandex there is Alice ask them a
да есть Яндекс есть Алиса спроси у них
school where teaching is in
школа в котором преподавание на
Ukrainian and that's it either there is
украинском языке и всё оно либо есть
a link it gives you if there is none then it doesn't
тебе ссылку выдаёт если нету Значит не
give you what look good And if
выдаёт ты что смотри хорошо А если
good if there is none then what well if there is none then
хорошо если нету то что ну если нету
we will
тогда мы поймём что нету давай так Ну
understand that there is none let's do it Well okay Well let's assume that there are none there are none yes Okay
хорошо Ну давай предположим что их нет
let's continue in the Buryat
нету да О'кей давай дальше на бурятском
language there is at least one
языке есть хоть одна
school good No and no in Bashkir
школа хорошо Нет и нет на башкирском
there is a language no and How is it that
есть языке нет и Во как так получается
Russia is a multinational
что Россия многонациональное
state look again Ukraine is
государство ещ раз смотри Украина - это
Ukraine you live in
Украина ты живёшь в России ты живёшь в
Russia you live in Russia I am a person a citizen of
России я человек гражданин
Russia I tell you again [ __ ] I am a
России Я тебе ещ раз говорю сри Я
Russian who Well how is Russian
русский который Ну как русский
half Circassian half Russian yes
наполовину черкес наполовину русский да
who was born in Belgorod Yes who
который родился в Белгороде Да который
now lives in Kharkov my child
сейчас живёт в Харькове у меня ребнок
goes to third grade
ходит в третий класс на русском языке
speaks Russian soon it is forbidden no
говорит скоро запрещено
one has crossed look our
никто не перел смотри у нас директор
school principal speaks Russian our children
школы говорит по-русски у нас дети
speak Who speaks Russian who speaks English
говорят Кто по-русски кто по-английски
no one will forbid less Listen some
никто не запретит меньше Слушай какие-то
you couldn't find for me  on the website of the Verkhovna
ты мне не смог найти на сайте Верховной
Rada Yes, you couldn't do this bill on the ban
Рады Да этот законопроект о запрете ты
You
не смог Ничего ты вообще за весь
couldn't find anything at all during the entire conversation to
разговор ничего не смог найти в
confirm your words You piled on
подтверждении своих слов ты навали
some theses I'm saying that it's good that
какие-то тезисы Я же говорю что
you pour out some theses Yes, but
хороо ты наливаешь какие-то тезисы Да но
you don't confirm It doesn't seem to you
ты не подтверждаешь Тебе не кажется
This says that you don't
Это говорит о том что ты который не
filter information and don't
фильтру информацию и не задумываешься
even think Well, I rely on facts Yes, I live
даже ну я на фактах опираюсь да я живу
now If I lived in the Belgorod
сейчас если бы я жил в Белгородской
region Yes, I would have thought before that maybe there is an
области да Раньше я бы думал что может
absolutely oppressed
там утесняемый абсолютно
[music]
[музыка]
Russia is bombing Russian-speaking Kharkov,
Россия бомбит русскоязычный
just stupidly Russian-speaking Kharkov is bombing Russian-speaking Bakhmut They
Харьков просто тупо русскоязычный
destroyed it completely There were 70,000
уничтожили вообще под ноль 70.000
people, not a single house was
человек было ни одного дома не
left This is just
оставили Это просто ужас
some kind of horror That is, if Russia Came here to
какой-то То есть если Россия Пришла тут
defend the Russian language of
что-то защищать русский язык
Russian-speakers, why is it destroying
русскоязычных зачем она уничтожает
Russian-speaking cities in Kharkov,
русскоязычные города у нас в Харькове
right here Yes, I had a neighbor of ours at the
вот тут Да наш у меня соседка была по
kiosk, she herself was originally from the
киос она сама вообще родом из
Stavropol Territory She had a husband during the Soviet Union
Ставропольского края Она при Союзе у неё
military they came to Kharkov
муж был военный они приехали в Харьков
like in general Aunt Bella was so
типа вообще тётя Белла такая была
good
хорошая
Yes she
Да
died you know
погибла знаешь
how without a clue just like that she was driving to
как без понятия вот так ехала просто на
work driving to
работу ехала на
work a rocket hit the neighboring house with
работу ракета в соседний дом попала
shrapnel
осколками
wounded so a woman 68
ранила так женщина 68
years old a sweet creature Russian-speaking she
лет милое создание русскоязычное она
speaks Ukrainian she didn’t beat a dick at all
по-украински вообще дупля не отбивала
she was from Stavropol her husband
она родом со Ставрополя муж у неё
was some kind of military man also I don’t know where
военный какой-то был тоже не знаю откуда
he was from you I didn’t know my husband my husband died a long time ago
он ти я мужа не знал муж уже погиб давно
Well what can I say it’s a pity the woman is generally
Ну что я сказать жаль женщина вообще она
Russian who lives in Kharkov Russian
русская которая живёт в Харькове русско
She you know when we were on first name terms with each other I felt
Она знаешь мы когда вот мы на ты был ког
sorry for any people at all e
мне вообще любых людей жал
Kio communicated
э Кио общались
she said Andryushenka She annoyed me a little she said Andryushenka to me yes Well I said say
немножко она говорила Андрюшенька на
Andrey She says
меня да Вот я говорил говорите Андрей
No you are younger than me I
Она говорит Нет ты младше меня я тебя
will call you
Андрюшенька буду называть она го
Andryushenka she go Andryushenka I myself am Russian Katy says
Андрюшенька я сама русская каты говорит
but I hate this Putin he says
но я вот этого Путина ненавижу говорит
why is
зачем
he here and says he bombs people he
он вот тут людей и говорит он бомбит он
says that  he came to protect me, a
говорит что он пришёл защищать меня
Russian speaker, and drops bombs on
русскоязычную да и скидывает бомбы на
my city and she says, And if I
мой город и она говорит А если я
die, the words of the prophet, the logic diverges a little
погибну проро слова немного логика
because it
расходится потому
seemed to me absolutely adequate that
что мне показалось абсолютно адекватным
your argument is that Russia is not at war with
ваш аргумент в том что Россия не воюет с
Ukraine, but Russia is fighting more with Europe.
Украиной а Россия воюет больше с Европой
I agree here. Here, the fact that
тут я согласен Вот А в этом то что там
Putin came to protect the Russian language is
Путин пришёл защищать русский язык это
also a kind of narrative because behind
же тоже некий нарратив потому что за
this lies another thing, that he has been
этим кроется же другое что вот он
talking for more than 10 years in a row about the fact that
говорил больше 10 лет подряд о том что
Ukraine should not join NATO and he
Украина не должна вступать в НАТО и он
told us, we Russian-speakers,
говорил нам нам русскоязычным
this is clearly told to us that they are supposedly protecting
это нам чётко говорят что типа защищают
Russian-speakers. Well, Andrey, I didn’t
русскоязычных Ну Андрей я же не
interrupt, let’s finish, and he has been
перебивал давай договори вот и он
talking for
говорил на протяжении
probably more than 10 years, no NATO,
там наверное больше 10 лет никакого НАТО
no NATO, no NATO, he has been
никакого НАТО никакого НАТО всё время он
talking about this all the time, and in 201,
об этом говорил и в 201
Ukraine adopts a law on joining
году Украина принимает закон о вхождении
NATO in the Constitution, after which,
в НАТО в Конституцию после чего
naturally, things in Russia are very bad,
естественно в России очень плохо вообще
very bad with propaganda, just awful.
очень плохо с пропагандой просто ужасно
Well, that is, I have probably never seen worse propaganda,
Ну то есть хуже пропаганды наверное я не
and in general, communication with the population is
видел и вообще общение с населением
very bad. And after that  something of their
очень плохое Вот и после чего начинается
own begins and people need to explain it somehow and they
сво и людям надо это как-то объяснить и
say there are fascists and so on yes
говорят вот там фашисты и так далее да
it is a place to be but not on such a
это есть место быть но не такого
scale Yes, to start something of their own there but the
масштаба Да чтобы начинать там сво но
main reason that I
основная причина которую я для себя
explain to myself is of course joining
объясняю это конечно же вступление в
NATO Well, okay, but why did you see
НАТО Ну хорошо а вот зачем ты же видел
the news Yes, that Russia is dropping guided aerial bombs on our
новости Да что Россия сбрасывает на наш
Kharkov
Харьков
Yes, I see that they are
управляемые Да я смотрю там вообще по
dropping them all over Ukraine, not all over
всей Украине сбрасывает не по всей
Ukraine, there are these Kheds and missiles flying there yes, and
Украине там летят эти Хеды и ракеты да а
this is a cap what is it they are
это кап что это такое они из
launching from the Belgorod region I have
Белгородской области запускают У меня же
friends there they see this
там знакомые они видет с самолёта эту
guided bomb from an airplane and it flies to Kharkov
управляемую бомбу и она до Харькова
And a half-ton falls you understand what
долетает И падает полутон ная понимаешь
it is when a
что такое в жилой массив прилетает
half-ton
полутон ная
bomb flies into a residential area to be honest I can't imagine I don't
бомба честно говоря не представляю Не
even want to imagine but look and
хочу даже себе представлять а вот смотри
we imagine because I have
а у нас представляют потому что у меня
another wait so look why why is it
есть ещ подожди так смотри зачем зачем
dropping aerial bombs on Kharkov on a residential area
на Харьков на жилую застройку скидывает
I have another
авиабомбы У меня есть ещё такой
comment when
комментарий когда
may the Kingdom of Heaven be to this woman who
э Царство небесное этой женщине которая
says that she is not a white  Aunt
говорит что она не а т бела тётя
Bella Bella Lvovna if so she
Белла Белла Львовна если так что она
hates Putin because he attacked
ненавидит Путина потому что вот он напал
I have exactly the same counter question And
у меня точно такой же встречный вопрос А
you have no complaints about your president
у вас нет претензии к вашему президенту
Well that is, this is a unipolar world I will
Ну то есть это однополярный мир я
explain what reasons for this did not
объясню ких причин к этому не
exist that is, the Lovek went crazy And
существовало то есть ловек сошёл с ума И
suddenly I do not have a Ukrainian passport I am a
вдруг у меня нету паспорта Украины Я
citizen of the Russian Federation they did not
гражданин Российской Федерации мне не
give me like well after the fourteenth year I
выдали типа ну после четырнадцатого года
hardly even think that they would give me
вряд ли даже думае что мне бы дали
citizenship yes that is, I remain a
гражданство да то есть я остаюсь
citizen of the Russian Federation I have a
гражданином Российской Федерации у меня
passport of the Russian Federation that is why Zelensky is not
паспорт РФ вот ээ поэтому Зеленский не
my president he is the President of the Ukrainians Yes
мой президент это Президент украинцев Да
and they should evaluate him yes as I see it yes
и им им его оценивать да как я вижу да
He protects the interests of
Он защищает интересы
his people Yes because they attacked
своего народа Да потому что напали на
him they are
него они
defending themselves Well that is, they lived well
защищаются Ну то есть Жили жили хорошо
Nothing happened And then suddenly Well how
Ничего не случилось И тут вдруг Ну как
Putin took Crimea captured Donetsk
Путин взял захватил Крым захватил Донецк
Lugansk and then went to in the second
Луганск да потом поехали в в д втором
year and went to Kharkov
году да на Харьков
one hundred vats don't interrupt
попёрли ста вате же не перебивайте
now there is just stupid destruction of
сейчас идт просто тупо уничтожение
Russian-speaking cities from Kharkov
русскоязычных городов из Харькова Вот
Look in Kharkov  yes, before the full-scale
смотри в Харькове да до полномасштабного
invasion,
вторжения
several million people lived there now
жило несколько миллионов людей сейчас
Kharkov residents are scattered around the world in general,
харьковчане вот раскиданы по миру вообще
Germany, Poland, and live in western Ukraine Yes,
Германия Польша на западе Украине живут
because it's scary We have a
Да потому что страшно У нас вот есть
microdistrict called Severnaya Saltovka, I don't live in NM Yes, it's
микрорайон Северная Салтовка я не на НМ
a little more convenient for me I'm
живу Да мне немножко удобнее Я на юге
a little more in the south Saltovka, it's just generally the
немного Салтовка она просто вообще там
most densely populated area of ​​Ukraine
самый густонаселённый район Украины
because he was
получается потому что он ещё с
so upset since the Soviet Union, he was upset there, there are a
Советского Союза так расстраивался
huge number of houses there And it's
расстраивался там домов огромное И он
just in the north, from the side closer
как раз на севере со стороны типа ближе
to Russia, it's just awful there, they're empty
к России там просто жесть там пустые
now when you go We came Because I
сейчас идёшь Мы приезжали Потому что я
signed up as a volunteer to deliver
записывался в волонтёры развозить
these products to pensioners, so the
пенсионерам эти продукты так вот мы с
guys and I and there are, uh, teams
ребятами и то есть есть ээ э команды
that give out products Yes, you just need to follow the
которые дают продукты Да нужно просто по
list because it's a huge
списку потому что это огромное
amount, you can
количество там ты можешь за вечера
circle 10 people in an evening because you go in to
обвести там 10 человек потому что зайти
pick them up and so on And so these
поднять и так дальше Да и так эти
teams and you come to the yard That's
команды и ты приезжаешь в двор
awful You look, there is, uh,
Вот это ужас Ты смотришь вот там есть ээ
on Saltovka That's Takar Yarosh Street
на Салтовке Вот это улица такара Яроша
And you come there stupidly  In short,
И ты приходишь там тупо Короче вымерло
everything died out, there are yards in which there are
всё вымерла есть дворы в которых людей
no people, the neighboring yard is a nine-story building
нет соседний двор девятиэтажка
destroyed, and in this yard everyone left
разбита А в этом дворе все выехали
because they are afraid that there will be an
потому что боятся что будет
attack, it is scary and pensioners live, we
прилёт страшно и пенсионеры живут мы
say, let's move, well, to the
говорим что давайте переезжайте Ну на
southern part, they are given certain
Южную часть там им дают определённые там
dormitories there and so on, no, grandma
общежития и так дальше нет бабушка
says, I lived here, I will die here,
говорит я тут жила я тут
Andrey, is there a question or
умру Андрей Есть ли вопрос или
comment on the fact that I feel sorry for people, I feel
комментарий к тому что жалко людей мне
absolutely sorry for
абсолютно жалко вобще
everyone, in general? If you feel sorry for people, how many
всех Если тебе жалко людей сколько
people Russia has already killed in
Россия убила уже людей в
Ukraine, I have no idea, well, what do you think,
Украине без понятия Ну как ты думаешь
one 10 100, you 10,000
один 10 100 ты 10.000
100,000, I really don't know, well,
100.000 Я правда не знаю Ну то есть
any assumption of mine will just be
любое моё предположение это будет просто
out of
с
thin air, well, let's go by your estimates, 10
потолка Ну давай по твоим оценкам 10
people were
человек
killed, exactly killed, I don't know, maybe
убило именно убило не знаю может быть
10 Ukrainians have already died in Russia's war against Ukraine,
войны России против Украины 10 человек
well, I think so, 100
украинцев погибло уже Ну я думаю да 100
people have
человек
probably died, but again, I say that
погибло наверно но опять же я говорю что
everyone, in the sense of you, you I'm not sure, or
все в смысле ты ты Не уверен Или погибла
100 Ukrainians have died in these 3 years,
за эти 3 года 100
no, I'm not
украинцев Нет не
sure, well, that is  it can or it
уверен Ну то есть это может или это
can be or more or less That is,
может быть или больше или меньше То есть
you just now you understand that it is
ты просто сейчас ты же понимаешь что это
more Yes, you understand that uh, children
больше Да ты понимаешь что ээ детей
only more than a thousand
только больше тысячи
dead it is by name by name there is here in
погибших это поимённо поимённо есть вот
here in Kharkov Yes, in
у нас в у нас в Харькове Да у нас в
Kharkov if you know they made an alley of
Харькове если знаешь сделали аллею
angels like this children citizens of Ukraine
ангелов такую дети граждане Украины
who died from Russian occupiers
которые погибли от российских оккупантов
perhaps Andrey I say I I don’t know
возможно Андрей я говорю я я не знаю
because the numbers are after
потому что цифры - это вот спустя
so many years of studying the Great
столько лет изучения Великой
Patriotic War again there they say
Отечественной войны опять же там говорят
many
многие
say 6 ml Who says 8 ml once a
говорит 6 мл Кто говорит 8 мл раз
believer the range is colossal I
верующий человек разбег колоссальный Я
believe that I believe in my own way Well, you are an
верю что я верю по-своему Ну ты
Orthodox Christian I am baptized but I believe in my
православный я крещённый но я верю
own way Well, that is, you do not mind if I
по-своему Ну то есть ты не против если я
pray for the souls of dead children no, I am not
помолюсь за души умерших детей нет не
against of course I am not against
против конечно я вообще не против
any Faith at all or when someone prays
никакой Веры или когда кто-то молится
just not Well, just let me I already
только не Ну просто нехай я уже один раз
prayed once T the person laughed at me a little
молился Т человек смеялся мне немножко
No, it’s
Нет мне это
funny to me It’s not funny to me Lord
смешно Для меня это не смешно Господи
Jesus Accept not the wine of the murdered citizens of
Иисусе Прими не вино убиенных граждан
Ukraine into your arms and there with this
Украины в объятия свои а там этим
Russians burn all these who
русским сожги этих всех которые
support the war against Ukraine
поддерживают войну против Украины
who are hypocritical like this one
которые лицемерные как вот
Russia Glory to Ukraine That's
России Слава Украине
what they are like I don't know what or
Вот это какие они Да какие не знаю или
more than 100 died I don't know Everything he
больше 100 погибло Да не знаю Всё что он
was piling on about Ukraine Yes It turns out he can't
наваливал про Украину Да Оказывается он
Nagulino studied he can't pour he can't
нагулино учился он не может налить не
school he can't
может школу не может
Tony they kill people in Ukraine they
Тони убивают людей в Украине
laugh at this I don't know there is a
смеются с это я не знаю есть
sheet it's a pity for this
листо жалко эту
granny It's a pity yes you watch take it
бабушку Жалко это да ты посмотри возьми
Open the video and see what they are
Открой видео и посмотри что с Харьковом
doing to Kharkov what they did to Bakhmut what they
делают что с бахмутом сделали что с
did to Mariupol today is the 10th
мариуполем сделали сегодня сте число
anniversary when Russian terrorists
годовщина когда российские террористы
dropped air bombs on the Drama Theater in
скинули авиабомб на Драмтеатр в
Mariupol how many children died
Мариуполе сколько погибло детей
But about Ukraine about something there he googles
Зато про Украину о что-то там всё гуглит
everything he knows That's how well
всё знает Вот
we did it as best we
так ну мы его как
could
могли
But these are just such cynical
Но это просто настолько циничные
heartless people so much it's not
бездушные люди настолько это же он не
just him yes we he came out here specifically to
просто да мы он вышел сюда специально об
talk about this Yes he hates
этом поговорить Да он ненавидит
hates Ukraine and Ukrainians he has
ненавидит Украину и украинцев у него
this hatred just like him
прямо эта ненависть есть так же как он
Who is watching us yes  from Russia from other
Кто у нас смотрит да из России из других
countries from other nations how do they
стра из других народов как к вам
treat you Yes to some
относятся Да к каким-то
Papuans and what for schools in Bashkor
папуаса а что зачем школы на башкор ском
in Tatar Yes in Buryat we do
на татарском Да на бурятском у нас же
n't have schools in
нет школ на
Papuans that's it like write a comment and
папуас вот так вот лайк писка комент и
send this video to everyone I know
скиньте це видео всм знам
subscribe to my Ista I don't know why it's for
подпишись на мий Иста Я не знаю для чого
you why else you should watch on my
це тоб для чого ще тоб там дивитись на
face But for you it's one two
оцей мий фейс Але для тебе це один два
or three clicks But you try me and I
або три клика Але ти тримае мене и я
will be like Wow I have a lot of fouls and
буду кти Вау в мене там Купа фолов и в
I will be in a great mood to do New
мене буде класний настр щоб робити Нови
cool video letter on Instagram bye
крут видео пись на й Instagram пок
Andriy Oh
Андрий О
so let me
так давай я тебе
wait for you and
чекаю а